Register of the Frank A. Golder papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- American Relief Administration, 1919-1929
  - European Operations
    - Correspondence
      - Adams, Ephraim D., 1920-1923
        Box/Folder 22: 15
      - Bibinoff, S., 1922
        Box/Folder 22: 16
      - Boyd, J. H., 1923
        Box/Folder 22: 17
      - Bryant, Colonel, 1921
        Box/Folder 22: 18
      - De Jacobs, John F., 1925
        Box/Folder 22: 19
      - Hart, Hector McBean, 1922
        Box/Folder 22: 20
      - Haskell, W. N., 1922
        Box/Folder 22: 21
      - Herron, Professor, 1922
        Box/Folder 23: 1
      - Herter, Christian
        - 1922
          Box/Folder 23: 2
        - 1922-1923 (Reel 29)
          Box/Folder 23: 3
        - 1923
          Box/Folder 23: 4
      - Kelley, William, 1922
        Box/Folder 23: 5
      - Lazurskii, V., 1922
        Box/Folder 23: 6
      - Lutz, Ralph, undated
        Box/Folder 23: 7
      - Vinogradov, A. K., 1922
        Box/Folder 23: 8
    - Historical Division records
      - All-Russian Commercial Conference
        Box/Folder 23: 9
      - "Gross Revenue of Farming in the Agricultural Year", 1922-1923
        Box/Folder 23: 10
      - Wage system
        Box/Folder 23: 11
    - Subject File
      - Central Relief Commission for Scientists, 1921-1922
        Box/Folder 23: 12
      - Communist Manifesto, translated into various Eastern languages, 1922 December 4
        Box/Folder 23: 13. Printed copies
      - Dagestan
        - General, 1919-1923
          Box/Folder 23: 14
        - German Mennonite Colony
          Box/Folder 23: 15
      - Figner, Vera
        Box/Folder 23: 15A
      - Hutchinson, Lincoln
        Box/Folder 23: 16
      - Khar'kov region - Sanitary conditions
        Box/Folder 23: 17
      - Maps (Reel 30)
        Box/Folder 24: 1
      - Radek, Karl, Interview with, 1922 June 8
        Box/Folder 24: 2
      - Relations with the Soviet government
        - General
          Box/Folder 24: 3
        - Conference between Governor Goodrich and Representatives of the Soviet government, 1922 June 19
          Box/Folder 24: 4
      - Russian family expenses, 1910, 1918-1920
        Box/Folder 24: 5
      - Russian Orthodox Church - Relations with the Soviet government
        Box/Folder 24: 6
      - Soviet Union
        - Agriculture
          Box/Folder 24: 7
        - Budget, 1922
          Box/Folder 24: 8
        - Constitution
          Box/Folder 24: 9
        - Cultural and scientific institutions
          Box/Folder 24: 10
        - Economic conditions, 1918-1922
          Box/Folder 24: 11
        - Education
          - General
            Box/Folder 24: 12
          - Elementary schools (Reel 31)
            Box/Folder 24: 13
        - History - Revolution, 1917-1921
          - General
            Box/Folder 24: 14
          - Miliukov, Paul, "A New Period of the Russian Anti-Bolshevist Struggle,", 1921
            Box/Folder 24: 15
          - Sokolov, N. D., memoirs of conversations, undated
            Box/Folder 24: 16
        - Industry, 1922
          Box/Folder 24: 17
        - Labor. Questionnaires for employment applicants
          Box/Folder 24: 18
        - Land policy, 1922
          Box/Folder 24: 19
        - Scholars and scientists
          Box/Folder 25: 1
        - Social conditions, 1919-1922
          Box/Folder 25: 2
        - University faculty and students
          - General
            Box/Folder 25: 3-4
          - Student relief
            Box/Folder 25: 5
        - Wage system, 1922
          Box/Folder 25: 6
      - Tsentral'nyi Komitet Vserossiiskogo Soiuza Rabotnikov Prosveshcheniia, 1922
        Box/Folder 25: 7
      - Ufa District, Work of the A.R.A. in the, Descriptive memorandum by William J. Kelley, 1922 July
        Box/Folder 25: 8
      - Ukraine
        - General. Map, 1921
          Box/Folder 25: 9
        - Agriculture and population, 1921
          Box/Folder 25: 10
        - History -, 1914-1916
          Box/Folder 25: 11
    - Volga Basin, - Trip of F. Golder, 1921
      Box/Folder 25: 12
    - Miscellaneous
      Box/Folder 25: 13
- Subject File, 1861-1929
  Correspondence, reports, memoranda, clippings, lists, notes, transcripts, printed matter and miscellany. Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Alaska - Description and travel - Lopp, W. J., "Log of the Overland Relief Expedition,", 1896-1959
    Box/Folder 25: 14
  - Alaska - Description and travel - Lopp, W. J., "Log of the Overland Relief Expedition,", 1896-1959 (Reel 32)
    Box/Folder 25: 15
  - American Red Cross Mission to Russia
    Box/Folder 25: 16
  - Americans in the Near East
    Box/Folder 25: 17
  - Armenian question, 1918-1920
    Box/Folder 25: 18
  - Armenians in Turkey, 1919-1920
    Box/Folder 25: 19
  - Austria - History -, 1918-1938
    - Hertz, Friedrich, "The Problem of Austria,", undated
      Box/Folder 25: 20
    - Redlich, Josef, "The Problem of the Austrian Republic,", 1920 July
      Box/Folder 25: 21
  - Austro-Hungarian Empire, Dismemberment of. Report by W. B. Causey, 1921 April 1
    Box/Folder 26: 1
  - Austro-Hungarian prisoners of war in Albania, 1921
    Box/Folder 26: 2
  - Balkan Peninsula - History -, 1914-1916
    Box/Folder 26: 3
  - Baltic States
    - General
      Box/Folder 26: 4
    - American Red Cross in Riga, Latvia, 1919-1920
      Box/Folder 26: 5
    - Foreign relations
      - Russia, 1920
        Box/Folder 26: 6
      - Ruthenia
        Box/Folder 26: 7
    - History
      - Pre-20th century
        Box/Folder 26: 8
      - 1918-1921
        Box/Folder 26: 9
    - Religion
      Box/Folder 26: 10
  - Belgian Army. Cammaerts, Emile, "The Work of the Army,", undated
    Box/Folder 26: 11
  - Bulgaria
    - Foreign relations - Serbia, 1923
      Box/Folder 26: 12
    - Territorial questions, 1919
      Box/Folder 26: 13
    - Treaties, 1914-1921
      Box/Folder 26: 14
  - Coal production and transportation in Central Europe. Report by W. B. Causey, 1920 December 12
    Box/Folder 26: 15
  - Commission for Relief in Belgium. Dowding, W. E.
    - Draft report, undated
      Box/Folder 26: 16
    - "The Romance of Voluntary Effort,", 1915 May 1
      Box/Folder 26: 17
  - Education in the Near East, 1920
    Box/Folder 26: 18
  - Estonian Army, 1918
    Box/Folder 26: 19
  - France - Foreign relations - Italy
    - "Carthage" affair, 1913
      Box/Folder 26: 20
    - "Manouba" affair, 1912
      Box/Folder 26: 21
    - "Tavignano" affair, 1912
      Box/Folder 26: 22
  - Gogian, Vahan
    Box/Folder 26: 23
  - Hague Conference (2nd: - Russian participation, 1907)
    Box/Folder 26: 24
  - Haight, Hector C. (Reel 33)
    Box/Folder 26: 25
  - Hoover War Library
    - Acquisitions lists, 1922-1925
      Box/Folder 26: 26
    - Acquisitions lists, 1922-1925
      Box/Folder 27: 1
    - Functions of the Directors
      Box/Folder 27: 2
  - Hopi Indians. Murphy, Matthew, "The Snake Dance People and Their Country,", 1928
    Box/Folder 27: 3
  - Hungary
    - Agriculture, 1914-1920
      Box/Folder 27: 4
    - Armed forces, 1914
      Box/Folder 27: 5
    - Foreign relations
      - Serbia. Letter from Count Stephan Tisza to Professor Marczali, 1918 January 25
        Box/Folder 27: 6
      - United States of America, 1921
        Box/Folder 27: 7
    - History - 1917-1919. War journal by Dr. Eugen Ronay de Bars
      Box/Folder 27: 8
    - Politics and government, 1914
      Box/Folder 27: 9
    - Return of King Charles IV, 1921 March-April (Reel 34)
      Box/Folder 27: 10
  - Interallied Rhineland High Commission, 1921-1922
    Box/Folder 27: 11
  - International Naval Conference, 1908-1909
    Box/Folder 27: 12
  - Latvia
    - Description. Ballod, Dr. C., "Latvia,", undated
      Box/Folder 27: 13
    - Diplomats
      Box/Folder 27: 14
    - Education, 1920s
      Box/Folder 27: 15
    - Foreign relations - Russia
      Box/Folder 27: 16
    - History -, 1918-1940
      - General
        Box/Folder 27: 17
      - War of Independence, 1918-1920. Haken, Mary von, "Meine Bolshewiken Erlebnisse,"
        Box/Folder 27: 18
      - Soviet attempt at establishing a communist Latvia
        Box/Folder 28: 1
        - 1919
          Box/Folder 28: 2
    - Land reform, 1920
      Box/Folder 28: 3
    - Politics and government, 1917-1921
      Box/Folder 28: 4
    - Social conditions, 1920s
    - Statesmen
      Box/Folder 28: 5
      - General
        Box/Folder 28: 6
      - Ulmanis, Karl
  - Lithuania
    - Church affairs, 1920
      Box/Folder 28: 7
    - History
      - 1870-1920
        Box/Folder 28: 8
      - 1919
        Box/Folder 28: 9
  - Maps (Reel 35)
    Box/Folder 28: 10
  - Moore, Edwin and Theodore, 1861-1865
    Box/Folder 28: 11
  - Mormon Battalion Monument. Souvenir brochure, 1927 May 30
    Box/Folder 28: 12
  - Navajo Indians
    Box/Folder 28: 13
  - Near East relief, 1921
    Box/Folder 28: 14
  - Nicholas II, Emperor of Russia, stationery
    Box/Folder 28: 15.
  - North Sea Incident, 1904
    Box/Folder 28: 16
  - Overland Expedition, 1897-1898
    Box/Folder 28: 17
  - Pacifism. Jordan, David Starr
    - "Journey to Switzerland and Germany, ", 1916 November 6 - December 4
      Box/Folder 28: 18
    - "What Shall We Say?", 1915
      Box/Folder 28: 19
  - Paris International Aeronautical Conference, November 1910
    Box/Folder 28: 20
  - Paris Peace Conference, delegation propaganda, 1919
    Box/Folder 29: 1
  - Philosophy
    - Peresvet (Murav'ev, V.), "The Regeneration of the World,", 1923 May 23
      Box/Folder 29: 2
    - Russel, Nicholas, essays on Eastern and Western philosophy
      Box/Folder 29: 3
  - Pobedonostsev, K. P.
    Box/Folder 29: 4
  - Poland - Social conditions - 1920. Fuller, W. Parmer, "Continuing the Narrative,", 1920 March 14
    Box/Folder 29: 5
  - Rapallo Agreement, December 1, 1920
    Box/Folder 29: 6
  - Red Putilovetz (Krasnyi Putilovets) (Reel 36)
    Box/Folder 29: 7
  - Russia
    - Copyright law, 1911
      Box/Folder 29: 8
    - Economic conditions - 20th century
      - General
        Box/Folder 29: 9-12
      - General (Reel 37)
        Box/Folder 30: 1-2
      - Ration cards for sugar, Petrograd, 1916
        Box/Folder 30: 3
    - Foreign policy -, 1904-1906
      Box/Folder 30: 4-5
    - Foreign relations
      - China, 1880-1922
        Box/Folder 30: 6
      - Turkey, 1911-1912 (Reel 38)
        Box/Folder 30: 7
      - United States of America
        - 19th century
          Box/Folder 30: 8
        - 1905
          Box/Folder 30: 9
        - 1905
          Box/Folder 31: 1-2
        - 1916
          Box/Folder 31: 3
    - Gosudarstvennaia Duma, 1914
      Box/Folder 31: 4. Entrance passes
    - History
      - 17th century manuscripts
        Box/Folder 31: 5
      - Arkhangelsk Gospels facsimile, early 20th century (Reel 39)
        Box/Folder 31: 6. Early 20th century facsimile of the 11-12th century Gospels from the Rumiantsev Museum.
      - 17th century manuscripts
        Box/Folder 32: 1
      - February Revolution, 1917-1921
        Box/Folder 32: 2
    - Ministerstvo Narodnago Prosveshcheniia. Imperatorskoe Obshchestvo Istorii i Drevnostei Rossiiskikh, 1893-1904
      Box/Folder 32: 3
    - Politics and government, 1911-1916
      Box/Folder 32: 4
    - Social conditions, 1801-1917
      Box/Folder 32: 5
    - Treaties with Japan, 1906-1907
      Box/Folder 32: 6
  - Russian Academy of Sciences, Bicentenary Celebration, 1925 September
    Box/Folder 32: 7
  - Russian Far East, 1921
    - Mining industry
      Box/Folder 32: 8
    - Natural resources
      Box/Folder 32: 9
    - Primorskaia Okruzhnaia Torgovo-Promyshlennaia Palata
      - "Puti Soobshcheniia Dal'niago Vostoka," Vladivostok, 1921
        Box/Folder 32: 10
      - "Vypiski iz protokolov zasedanii, Oktiabr'"
        Box/Folder 32: 11
  - Russian Refugees Relief Association, London
    Box/Folder 32: 12
  - Russians in Constantinople, refugees from Crimea, 1921
    Box/Folder 32: 13
  - Russians in Czechoslovakia, 1922-1927
    Box/Folder 32: 14
  - Russians in Northern California, Fort Ross, 19th century (Reel 40)
    Box/Folder 32: 15
  - Russians in Serbia, 1920s
    Box/Folder 33: 1
  - Russo-Japanese War, 1904-1905
    Box/Folder 33: 2-3
  - Slavs in the U.S., 1917
    Box/Folder 33: 4
  - Soviet Union
    - Budget, 1922-1923
      Box/Folder 33: 5
    - Calendar, 1920 January
      Box/Folder 33: 6
    - Civil and criminal justice, 1920
      Box/Folder 33: 7
    - Coins and currency, notes on
      Box/Folder 33: 8
    - Communist Party of the Soviet Union. Fifth Congress. Resolutions
      Box/Folder 33: 8A
    - Economic policy
      - General, 1922
        Box/Folder 33: 9
      - Litoshenko, Lev, "Socialization of the Land in Russia,", 1922
        - Russian version
          Box/Folder 33: 10
        - Russian version (Reel 41)
          Box/Folder 33: 11-12 and 34: 1-2
        - English translation
          Box/Folder 34: 3-4
    - Economic, political and social conditions, Goodrich, James, 1917-1923.
      - Documents collected by Goodrich
        Box/Folder 34: 5
      - Documents composed by Goodrich
        - Correspondence
          - Golder, Frank, 1923 (Reel 42)
            Box/Folder 34: 6
          - Harding, Warren G., 1922-1923
            Box/Folder 34: 7
          - Herter, Christian, 1922
            Box/Folder 34: 8
          - Hoover, Herbert, 1922-1923
            Box/Folder 34: 9
          - Hughes, Charles Evans, 1921-1922
            Box/Folder 34: 10
        - Diary
          Box/Folder 34: 11
        - Memorandum, 1922 June-July
          Box/Folder 34: 12
        - Notes
          Box/Folder 34: 13
    - Foreign relations - Poland, 1918-1920
      Box/Folder 34: 14
    - Gosudarstvennyi Bank, 1922
      Box/Folder 34: 15
    - History
      - Revolution, 1917-1921
        - General
          Box/Folder 34: 16 and 35: 1-3
        - General (Reel 43)
          Box/Folder 35: 4
        - Anti-Bolshevik songs
          Box/Folder 35: 5
        - Army, Unrest within
          Box/Folder 35: 6
        - Belenikhin, Ivan, "Begstvo,", 1920
          Box/Folder 35: 7
        - Benningsen, Count, an account of the Revolution (in Russian), 1921 March 3
          Box/Folder 35: 8
        - Got'e, Iurii V.
          - Correspondence and notes, 1918-1921
            Box/Folder 35: 9
          - Diary, holograph and typescript
            - 1917 (Reel 44)
              Box/Folder 35: 10
            - 1918
              Box/Folder 35: 11
            - 1919
              Box/Folder 35: 12
            - 1920
              Box/Folder 36: 1
            - 1921-1922
              Box/Folder 36: 2
        - Kornilov and Kaledin affair
          Box/Folder 36: 3
        - Kronshtadt Rebellion, 1921
          Box/Folder 36: 4
        - Murmansk agreement, 1918
          Box/Folder 36: 5
        - Onou, Alexander, "The Russian Revolution of 1917,", 1919 February 18 (Reel 45)
          Box/Folder 36: 6
        - Peresvet (Murav'ev, V.), "The Apocalypse of the Russian Revolution,", 1923 May 10
          Box/Folder 36: 7
        - Petrograd
          Box/Folder 36: 8
        - Zapadnaia Armiia (Western Army), 1919
          Box/Folder 36: 9-10. Includes Bermondt-Avalov correspondence
      - Allied intervention, 1918-1920
        Box/Folder 36: 11
    - Nutrition of population, 1922
      Box/Folder 36: 12
    - Trade - United States. Quarton, Harold B., "Raw Materials on Hand and Harbor Rehabilitation in Petrograd,", 1920 July 31
      Box/Folder 36: 13
  - Stanford University, Russian Institute. Agreement with Society of Cultural Relations of the USSR, undated
    Box/Folder 36: 14
  - Turkey
    - Americans in Constantinople, 1922
      Box/Folder 36: 15
    - Gates, C. P., "The Future of Constantinople,", 1920 August
      Box/Folder 36: 16
    - History - Revolution, 1918-1923
      Box/Folder 36: 17
    - Private schools
      Box/Folder 36: 18
    - Reed College, Constantinople, 1919 June
      Box/Folder 36: 19
    - Refugees in Constantinople, 1920
      Box/Folder 36: 20
  - United States
    - Foreign relations - Hungary. Material related to the American mission in Miskolcz, 1921
      Box/Folder 36: 21
    - History - Civil War, Letters, 1861-1865.
      Box/Folder 36: 22
  - Vooruzhennye Sily na Iuge Rossii (Reel 46)
    Box/Folder 37: 1
  - World War, 1914-1918
    - General. List of publications, 1920
      Box/Folder 37: 2
    - Constantinople
      Box/Folder 37: 3
    - Holzer, Joseph. Diary
      Box/Folder 37: 4
    - Russian mobilization, 1914 December 19
      Box/Folder 37: 5
  - Miscellaneous
    Box/Folder 37: 6-10
- Photographs, 1921-1929
  124 prints. Includes photographs of Frank Golder; American Relief Administration, European and Russian Operations, staff; conditions and victims of the famine in Russia, 1921-1923; cannibalism in Russia during the famine, 1921-1923; various scenes in Russia; various scenes in Latvia, primarily Kovno. Arranged by subject.
  - 4 prints of Frank Golder, circa 1928 (Envelope A)
  - 1 print depicting the staff of the American Relief Administration, European Operations, office in Copenhagen, 1920 (Envelope B)
  - 9 prints depicting American Relief Administration, Russian Operations, staff in Russia and Soviet government officials, 1921-1923 (Envelope C)
  - 81 prints depicting conditions and victims of the famine in Russia, 1921-1923 (Envelope D)
  - 81 prints depicting conditions and victims of the famine in Russia (cont.), 1921-1923 (Envelope E)
  - 81 prints depicting conditions and victims of the famine in Russia (cont.), 1921-1923 (Envelope F)
  - 81 prints depicting conditions and victims of the famine in Russia (cont.), 1921-1923 (Envelope G)
  - 81 prints depicting conditions and victims of the famine in Russia (cont.), 1921-1923 (Envelope H)
  - 81 prints depicting conditions and victims of the famine in Russia (cont.), 1921-1923 (Envelope I)
  - 11 prints depicting cannibalism in Russia during the famine of 1921-1923 (Envelope J)
  - 10 prints depicting various scenes in Russia, 1921-1923 (Envelope K)
  - 8 prints depicting various scenes in Latvia, primarily Kovno (Envelope L)